futures.io 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy - futures.io Forum

Last modified: October 7, 2016

This Privacy Policy discloses our privacy practices and the possible uses of the information that we gather on the futures.io Forum web site (“Website”). This policy can be modified at any time and it is your responsibility to observe any changes to the policy by reviewing this page on an ongoing basis.

**_Registration_**

Although registration is not required for general use of our Website, some areas on our Website do require registration. In order to complete the registration process, a user may be required to provide their contact information. This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site. It is optional for the user to provide any additional information, but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our Website. The password which you use to login to the Website account is encrypted before being saved in our database. Because of this, in case you forget your login password, we can't retrieve it for you; we are only able to change it to something else upon your written request to do so.

**_Information Collected_**

When you visit futures.io, we send one or more cookies to your web browser. A cookie is a small piece of information that is stored in your browser and can be referenced by our Website every time you visit our pages. Only the domain which set that cookie can access the information from it. Other domains can't access cookies set by us and we can't access cookies set by others.

Whenever your access a file from our website, the server may log data about your activity on the Website, and may include the following: (i) Requested URL, (ii) Your IP address, (iii) Date & Time of request, (iv) Your user agent, (v) Referring webpage (if any), (vi) Your Website username, and (vii) Size of the requested document.

In the process of creating an account on the Website, we may ask you for information, including your email address. This is done to assist with verifying your identity and to better support your use of the Website. Also, each thread, post, message you create on the Website is associated with your Website account & stamped with your IP address.

Email addresses you entered while registering on the Website are used to provide you updates of any content which you have subscribed to. Occasionally, we send out newsletters and/or important announcements regarding the changes in website, ongoing contests, webinars or events, etc. We may also email you promotional or marketing material from a paid advertiser on occasion. You may opt-out of any or all of these emails at your sole discretion - the body of the email will contain instructions for unsubscribing. The Website uses the information for responding to requests, customizing services and improving communications with our users. The Website does not sell or share personal information with any outside parties; however, we may share generalized information about users for the purpose of improving our Website.

**_Log Files_**

We may use Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to analyze trends, administer our site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**_Sharing_**

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

Your personally identifiable information is not retained, shared, stored or used by our third-party service providers, except in cases where the user has voluntarily signed up for their services. These third-party service providers are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

We may share content that you contribute to the site by way of other outlets, including but not limited to social media marketing.

**_Offsite Links_**

The Website contains numerous links to other sites. Please be aware that the Website is not responsible for the privacy practices of the sites to which we are linked. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of websites they visit.

**_Third-Party Advertising_**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personal information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

**_Third-Party Cookies_**

In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize "cookies" on your browser. We have no access to or control over the cookies used by our third-party advertisers.

**_Responsibility of Use_**

The Website is not responsible for user information collected by outside parties while visiting the Website. This includes information you voluntarily disclose through the use of forums, chats and e-mail, and information obtained through the use of links on our Website.

**_Consensual Use_**

The Website uses Google Adsense to serve advertisements relevant to the webpage content. To know more about what information Google collects and uses, read their [General Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html) and [Advertising Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) pages. If the Website desires the use of your information for purposes exclusive of this privacy policy, you will be contacted for consent prior to its use.

**_Notification of Policy Changes_**

Should our privacy policy change, notification will be posted on our Website. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, users will be notified via email. Upon notification, users will have a choice as to whether or not their information will be used in this manner. User information will be used in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

**_Contact Us_**

If you have any questions in regard to this Agreement, please contact us:

By using this site, you are agreeing to the [Disclaimers, Terms of Use and Terms and Conditions](https://futures.io/disclaimer/) as well as our [Privacy Policy](https://futures.io/privacy/).
